<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IISER Kolkata Movie Club on IKMC</title>
    <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IISER Kolkata Movie Club on IKMC</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 23:48:30 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iiserk-movie.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Submit Your Content!</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/pages/submit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 23:48:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/pages/submit/</guid>
      <description>Hey!&#xA;We at the IISER Kolkata Movie Club would love to hear what YOU have to say about cinema!&#xA;On this form, you can submit content that you have created regarding anything and everything related to cinema. This includes, but is not limited to&#xA;Movie Reviews Watch-lists (Subject / Film movement specific or otherwise) Movie Posters Blog-posts Short Films! If you want to put your content out there, we are here to help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer Movie Review Contest!</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/announcements/summer-movie-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 23:39:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/announcements/summer-movie-review/</guid>
      <description>Hello, lovers of good cinema!&#xA;The Movie Club of IISER Kolkata is thrilled to announce an exciting opportunity for all movie enthusiasts with some free time this summer – the Summer Movie Review Writing Contest! 📽️&#xA;Do you love watching movies and sharing your thoughts about them? Do you have a flair for writing and a passion for cinema? Do you overthink your ratings on Letterboxd? Or do you love a good movie and have never written a review?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Website Launch!</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/announcements/website-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 23:32:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/announcements/website-launch/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to launch our brand-new IISER Kolkata Movie Club website!&#xA;This will be the hub for all things cinema in IISER Kolkata - a place where we host reviews, posters, short films, etc. produced by our community of cinephiles.&#xA;This will also be where we keep you updated about upcoming screenings, and news regarding the club and its activities.&#xA;Looking forward to a thriving and lively online community!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Orange Bars &amp; Relationships – Thappad</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-orange-bars-relationships-thappad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-orange-bars-relationships-thappad/</guid>
      <description>Very rarely do I see a movie that has my eyes welling up with tears for the better part of the last act; even rarer is a Bollywood movie accomplishing this.&#xA;In an industry where ‘Kabir Singh’ exists and broke all records on opening day, ‘Thappad’ belongs to the rare breed of movies that has achieved this. Thappad is a powerhouse in itself – capably made, phenomenally executed, and refuses to pull any punches in the story it chooses to tell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping out two silhouettes: On the cinematic connection</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/uncategorized/mapping-out-two-silhouettes-on-the-cinematic-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/uncategorized/mapping-out-two-silhouettes-on-the-cinematic-connection/</guid>
      <description>Since a very early age I feel this innate tendency of trying to operate from inside my comfort zone. I have meant to do things without people knowing especially when they didn’t come across as even remotely doable. But at the same time there were always these deeply humanist emotions and overtly sentimental thought processes and now looking back I can never make out why the two character elements never clashed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Mind, Materialism &amp; Soul – Guide</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-mind-materialism-soul-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-mind-materialism-soul-guide/</guid>
      <description>I love different types of posters – my college wall is a testament to that. I have spent ages carefully curating what hangs on my wall, I have seen many posters, using the best digital nuances, illustrations and typography, but never have I seen anything that has shaken me this much.&#xA;It’s a simple poster, to be sure, but it is something I will carry with me for a very long time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cat Sticks (2019) : a chiaroscuro of love and loneliness</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cat-sticks-2019-a-chiaroscuro-of-love-and-loneliness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cat-sticks-2019-a-chiaroscuro-of-love-and-loneliness/</guid>
      <description>Navigating through Kolkata on a rainy November day to catch the Cat Sticks premiere was quite a task, with the traffic more arduous than usual, the rains incessant and heavy, and the passes at Nandan frequently running out. But the crowd at Nandan 1 spoke a different story at sundown — hundreds of people had turned up with umbrellas, waiting in queue in the downpour for more than an hour to attend the first ever Kolkata premiere for Cat Sticks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: Summer Wars</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/review-summer-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/review-summer-wars/</guid>
      <description>“Never turn your back on family, especially when they hurt you”&#xA;Summer Wars, is practically speaking, not the first movie that comes to mind when one thinks of director Mamoru Hosoda, especially when there’s The Girl Who Leapt Through Time. But in many ways Summer Wars crosses conventional stereotypes of animated movies to deliver a unique perspective to Japan’s family life and how a society deeply rooted into its history transitions into the modern world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love and Life in The Old West – The Ballad of Buster Scruggs</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/love-and-life-in-the-west-the-ballad-of-buster-scruggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/love-and-life-in-the-west-the-ballad-of-buster-scruggs/</guid>
      <description>I love the Coen Brothers.&#xA;I’m a deeply cynical person and I enjoy their distinctive brand of black comedy and dark drama.&#xA;…but this.&#xA;The Ballad of Buster Scruggs is a fascinating creature to behold. It is a movie put together from bits and pieces of cinematic tropes, conventions, and clichés, including ones borrowed from a range of genres, from ingenious physical comedy to romantic lyricism to Gothic horror. But all are united by a giddy Western revisionism centering upon a common theme: the relentless cruelty, wanton violence, deadly recklessness, and cavalier abuses of unchecked power that prevailed in the thinly and casually governed Wild West.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travis Bickle: A Character Analysis</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/travis-bickle-a-character-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/travis-bickle-a-character-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Taxi Driver, a 1976 neo-noir psychological thriller film, written by Paul Schrader and directed by Martin Scorsese is a first person character study of a New York City taxi driver named Travis Bickle, played by Robert De Niro who is well known for his distinctive method acting. The movie is narrated from the protagonist’s point of view and so if you want to enjoy the film, you have to fit yourself in his shoes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulp Fiction</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/pulp-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/pulp-fiction/</guid>
      <description>“And you know what they call a Quarter Pounder with Cheese in Paris? They call it a “Royale with Cheese.” -Vincent Vega from ‘Pulp Fiction’&#xA;As said by Roger Ebert, Quentin Tarantino is the Jerry Lee Lewis of cinema, a pounding performer who doesn’t care if he tears up the piano, as long as everybody is rocking. His movies are mostly characterized by satirical subject matters, a non-linear storyline, extended scenes of dialogues and aestheticization of violence, and Pulp Fiction is the supreme emblem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Artist – A Review</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/the-artist-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/the-artist-a-review/</guid>
      <description>‘The Sound of Silence’ could never be better conveyed than in a modern day black-and-white silent movie. Mingled with humour and drama, director Michel Hazanavicius has put forth with sheer brilliance the right ingredients to tickle not only your funny bone but also your brain, so much so that the movie could easily be mistaken for a classic. In the beautiful play of black and white, one gets to appreciate the ‘essence’ without much hindrance from ‘visual elements of color’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art and the artist: a cinematic viewpoint</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/art-and-the-artist-a-cinematic-viewpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/art-and-the-artist-a-cinematic-viewpoint/</guid>
      <description>In view of his recent death, I remembered how Bernardo Bertolucci admitted to have shot the infamous unscripted rape scene in Last Tango in Paris with Marlon Brando and Maria Schneider, the latter being kept completely in the dark about the scene because Bertolucci wanted to capture her reaction “as a girl, not as an actress”. Schneider took to drug abuse and depression surrounding the controversy that built for several years around the film, and died in 2011.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Into The Wild – A Review</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/into-the-wild-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/into-the-wild-a-review/</guid>
      <description>“Happiness only real when shared”&#xA;I chose to write a review on this because this is the last film I’d watched, and of course, there are many, many aesthetic films out there, but the beauty of this one is still as fresh in my mind as the “fresh-ness” of the numerous breathtaking scenes this film immortalises.&#xA;Directed by Sean Penn this film is, first and foremost, a journey of growth, self-realisation and understanding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Memoriam – Daredevil</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/in-memoriam-daredevil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/in-memoriam-daredevil/</guid>
      <description>“Let the Devil Out”.&#xA;Full disclosure here – I am, quite possibly a 5 year old, and love anything related to superheroes. I’ve seen almost all of WB’s “Arrowverse”. I survived the short-lived DCEU. And I’ve thoroughly enjoyed the Marvel Cinematic Universe.&#xA;But, Daredevil…&#xA;…Daredevil is a rare stroke of genius in an over saturated genre. Daredevil is the entire genre at its best – from the story telling and dialogues, to the themes, choreography and character arcs, Daredevil is a masterpiece.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>হলিউড ও বাংলা সিনেমাঃ একটি তুলনামূলক পাঠ</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/%E0%A6%B9%E0%A6%B2%E0%A6%BF%E0%A6%89%E0%A6%A1-%E0%A6%93-%E0%A6%AC%E0%A6%BE%E0%A6%82%E0%A6%B2%E0%A6%BE-%E0%A6%B8%E0%A6%BF%E0%A6%A8%E0%A7%87%E0%A6%AE%E0%A6%BE%E0%A6%83-%E0%A6%8F%E0%A6%95%E0%A6%9F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/%E0%A6%B9%E0%A6%B2%E0%A6%BF%E0%A6%89%E0%A6%A1-%E0%A6%93-%E0%A6%AC%E0%A6%BE%E0%A6%82%E0%A6%B2%E0%A6%BE-%E0%A6%B8%E0%A6%BF%E0%A6%A8%E0%A7%87%E0%A6%AE%E0%A6%BE%E0%A6%83-%E0%A6%8F%E0%A6%95%E0%A6%9F/</guid>
      <description>খুব সিরিয়াস একটি আলোচনা। গোটা লেখায় মোট এগারোবার ‘প্রেক্ষিত’ শব্দটা রয়েছে, সুতরাং সিরিয়াস হতেই হবে। অর্থাৎ কিনা গুরুতর মার্ক্সীয় দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি প্রভৃতি। একখানা প্রেক্ষিত এইসব বাঁদরামো করতেই খরচ হয়ে গেল (আরেকটা গেল এখানে)। এইপ্রকার ছ্যাবলামি ভবিষ্যতে চলবে না, আমি প্রবন্ধকার হিসেবে আপনাদের কথা দিচ্ছি পরবর্তী প্রেক্ষিতগুলি অতিশয় সচেতনতা ও পরিমিতিবোধের সহিত ব্যবহৃত হইবে। প্রেক্ষিত ছাড়াও একটা ভালো শব্দ আছে – ভাষ্য, যাকে বাংলায় বলে ন্যারেটিভ। প্রবন্ধটিতে কতবার ন্যারেটিভ শব্দটি রয়েছে সেটাও একটা দেখার বিষয়। যে লেখায় যত বেশিবার ন্যারেটিভ থাকে সে লেখা তত প্রগতিশীল বলে গণ্য হয়।</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Meditation on Heartbreak – October</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/a-meditation-on-heartbreak-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/a-meditation-on-heartbreak-october/</guid>
      <description>October is the closest that contemporary Hindi cinema has come to resembling an E. E. Cummings poem. Listen to the last verse of his famous poem – somewhere I have never travelled, gladly beyond. Cummings writes:&#xA;(I do not know what it is about you that closes&#xA;and opens; only something in me understands&#xA;the voice of your eyes is deeper than all roses&#xA;nobody, not even the rain, has such small hands)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorry To Bother You – A Review</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/sorry-to-bother-you-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/sorry-to-bother-you-a-review/</guid>
      <description>Cassius “Cash” Green, our protagonist, and an aptly named individual is at first trying to make ends meet. He is desperate enough to lie at an interview for a telemarketer job at RegalView, where he is caught, but gets a job anyway.&#xA;The whole movie is about the struggles working class in the world of late-stage capitalism. The most popular television show is “I Got The Shit Kicked Out of Me“, in which participants come and well… get the shit kicked out of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring, summer, fall, winter… and spring</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/spring-summer-fall-winter-and-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/spring-summer-fall-winter-and-spring/</guid>
      <description>I remember watching Spring, summer… one summer about eight years back on UTV world movies, and getting vaguely scarred by the image of a snake swimming around a boat on which monk is setting himself on fire. Not a good first impression, I agree. But time has flown past the handrails I held closely back then, and here I am, on a re-watch schedule of everything that got me curious at that age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Ladri di Biciclette” – A Review</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/ladri-di-biciclette-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/ladri-di-biciclette-a-review/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Rome wasn&amp;rsquo;t built in a day.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;When I was a kid, one of my chimerical longings of travelling to spellbinding whereabouts of the world included the emblematically beautiful city of Rome. It was only through rigorous high school history lessons later in my life that I came to learn about the poverty and political turmoil plaguing a traumatised Italy following World War II. Who could have thought that the once august Roman empire would wind up in such forlorn state with the passage of time?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 horror films for this Halloween</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/movielists/7-horror-films-for-this-halloween/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/movielists/7-horror-films-for-this-halloween/</guid>
      <description>Halloween season in full swing, possibly the best way to spend the upcoming weekend consists of a cup of coffee, a blanket, a horror-fest on your laptop and enormous courage!&#xA;Here are seven favorite horror films you can challenge yourself with!&#xA;The Shining (1980) The classic Stephen King novel adopted on screen by none other than the American maestro Stanley Kubrick. A house with a violent past, creepy corridors, ominous suspense, madness, murder, supernatural imagery, and everything you can think of that would lead to your worst nightmare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cinema Paradiso : On the emotions of every cinephile</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cinema-paradiso-on-the-emotions-of-every-cinephilic-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cinema-paradiso-on-the-emotions-of-every-cinephilic-soul/</guid>
      <description>“Cinema is the most beautiful fraud”&#xA;-Jean-Luc Godard&#xA;Indeed this resonates with all the hooligans, the elites, the children and the elderly who swarmed into a cinema hall day in day out in a wartime Sicilian village. This hall was the only one of it’s kind and went by the name of Cinema Paradiso. The name made perfect sense, as it stood as the grand abode of the multitude of films and exerted a divine presence which every human being desires to experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Nature of Memories – The House of Small Cubes</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-the-nature-of-memories-the-house-of-small-cubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-the-nature-of-memories-the-house-of-small-cubes/</guid>
      <description>Between my never ending binges on Netflix, I came across a very curious short film – The House of Small Cubes. It had a 97% match for me. Netflix had never let me down before with its recommendations (that is, indeed, how I discovered and binged BoJack Horseman before final exams – I wonder what that reveals about my current state of mind), so I decided to give it a try.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the IISER Kolkata Movie Club – your ticket to a cinematic adventure right here on campus! Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a die-hard film buff, a casual viewer, or someone who just loves the smell of popcorn, our club is the perfect place for you. We screen everything from classic masterpieces and indie gems to the latest blockbusters and thought-provoking documentaries.&#xA;Our club is more than just a place to watch movies; it’s a community of passionate cinephiles.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
