<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hollywood on IKMC</title>
    <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/tags/hollywood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hollywood on IKMC</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iiserk-movie.github.io/tags/hollywood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cat Sticks (2019) : a chiaroscuro of love and loneliness</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cat-sticks-2019-a-chiaroscuro-of-love-and-loneliness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cat-sticks-2019-a-chiaroscuro-of-love-and-loneliness/</guid>
      <description>Navigating through Kolkata on a rainy November day to catch the Cat Sticks premiere was quite a task, with the traffic more arduous than usual, the rains incessant and heavy, and the passes at Nandan frequently running out. But the crowd at Nandan 1 spoke a different story at sundown — hundreds of people had turned up with umbrellas, waiting in queue in the downpour for more than an hour to attend the first ever Kolkata premiere for Cat Sticks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love and Life in The Old West – The Ballad of Buster Scruggs</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/love-and-life-in-the-west-the-ballad-of-buster-scruggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/love-and-life-in-the-west-the-ballad-of-buster-scruggs/</guid>
      <description>I love the Coen Brothers. I’m a deeply cynical person and I enjoy their distinctive brand of black comedy and dark drama. …but this. The Ballad of Buster Scruggs is a fascinating creature to behold. It is a movie put together from bits and pieces of cinematic tropes, conventions, and clichés, including ones borrowed from a range of genres, from ingenious physical comedy to romantic lyricism to Gothic horror. But all are united by a giddy Western revisionism centering upon a common theme: the relentless cruelty, wanton violence, deadly recklessness, and cavalier abuses of unchecked power that prevailed in the thinly and casually governed Wild West.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travis Bickle: A Character Analysis</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/travis-bickle-a-character-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/travis-bickle-a-character-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Taxi Driver, a 1976 neo-noir psychological thriller film, written by Paul Schrader and directed by Martin Scorsese is a first person character study of a New York City taxi driver named Travis Bickle, played by Robert De Niro who is well known for his distinctive method acting. The movie is narrated from the protagonist’s point of view and so if you want to enjoy the film, you have to fit yourself in his shoes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulp Fiction</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/pulp-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/pulp-fiction/</guid>
      <description>“And you know what they call a Quarter Pounder with Cheese in Paris? They call it a “Royale with Cheese.” -Vincent Vega from ‘Pulp Fiction’&#xA;As said by Roger Ebert, Quentin Tarantino is the Jerry Lee Lewis of cinema, a pounding performer who doesn’t care if he tears up the piano, as long as everybody is rocking. His movies are mostly characterized by satirical subject matters, a non-linear storyline, extended scenes of dialogues and aestheticization of violence, and Pulp Fiction is the supreme emblem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Artist – A Review</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/the-artist-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/the-artist-a-review/</guid>
      <description>‘The Sound of Silence’ could never be better conveyed than in a modern day black-and-white silent movie. Mingled with humour and drama, director Michel Hazanavicius has put forth with sheer brilliance the right ingredients to tickle not only your funny bone but also your brain, so much so that the movie could easily be mistaken for a classic. In the beautiful play of black and white, one gets to appreciate the ‘essence’ without much hindrance from ‘visual elements of color’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Into The Wild – A Review</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/into-the-wild-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/into-the-wild-a-review/</guid>
      <description>“Happiness only real when shared”&#xA;I chose to write a review on this because this is the last film I’d watched, and of course, there are many, many aesthetic films out there, but the beauty of this one is still as fresh in my mind as the “fresh-ness” of the numerous breathtaking scenes this film immortalises.&#xA;Directed by Sean Penn this film is, first and foremost, a journey of growth, self-realisation and understanding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorry To Bother You – A Review</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/sorry-to-bother-you-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/sorry-to-bother-you-a-review/</guid>
      <description>Cassius “Cash” Green, our protagonist, and an aptly named individual is at first trying to make ends meet. He is desperate enough to lie at an interview for a telemarketer job at RegalView, where he is caught, but gets a job anyway.&#xA;The whole movie is about the struggles working class in the world of late-stage capitalism. The most popular television show is “I Got The Shit Kicked Out of Me“, in which participants come and well… get the shit kicked out of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cinema Paradiso : On the emotions of every cinephile</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cinema-paradiso-on-the-emotions-of-every-cinephilic-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cinema-paradiso-on-the-emotions-of-every-cinephilic-soul/</guid>
      <description>“Cinema is the most beautiful fraud” -Jean-Luc Godard&#xA;Indeed this resonates with all the hooligans, the elites, the children and the elderly who swarmed into a cinema hall day in day out in a wartime Sicilian village. This hall was the only one of it’s kind and went by the name of Cinema Paradiso. The name made perfect sense, as it stood as the grand abode of the multitude of films and exerted a divine presence which every human being desires to experience.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
