<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews and Discussions on IKMC</title>
    <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews and Discussions on IKMC</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Orange Bars &amp; Relationships – Thappad</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-orange-bars-relationships-thappad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-orange-bars-relationships-thappad/</guid>
      <description>Very rarely do I see a movie that has my eyes welling up with tears for the better part of the last act; even rarer is a Bollywood movie accomplishing this.&#xA;In an industry where ‘Kabir Singh’ exists and broke all records on opening day, ‘Thappad’ belongs to the rare breed of movies that has achieved this. Thappad is a powerhouse in itself – capably made, phenomenally executed, and refuses to pull any punches in the story it chooses to tell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Mind, Materialism &amp; Soul – Guide</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-mind-materialism-soul-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/on-mind-materialism-soul-guide/</guid>
      <description>I love different types of posters – my college wall is a testament to that. I have spent ages carefully curating what hangs on my wall, I have seen many posters, using the best digital nuances, illustrations and typography, but never have I seen anything that has shaken me this much.&#xA;It’s a simple poster, to be sure, but it is something I will carry with me for a very long time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cat Sticks (2019) : a chiaroscuro of love and loneliness</title>
      <link>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cat-sticks-2019-a-chiaroscuro-of-love-and-loneliness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iiserk-movie.github.io/posts/cat-sticks-2019-a-chiaroscuro-of-love-and-loneliness/</guid>
      <description>Navigating through Kolkata on a rainy November day to catch the Cat Sticks premiere was quite a task, with the traffic more arduous than usual, the rains incessant and heavy, and the passes at Nandan frequently running out. But the crowd at Nandan 1 spoke a different story at sundown — hundreds of people had turned up with umbrellas, waiting in queue in the downpour for more than an hour to attend the first ever Kolkata premiere for Cat Sticks.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
